welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in this video I'm going to show you how
在这段视频中 我将向您展示如何
to apply the speed effect under motion
在运动状态下应用速度效果
so we can change and make a video faster
这样我们就可以更快地改变和制作视频
or slower than it normally is so I'm
或者比平时慢 所以我
going to start by bringing in a clip
我们将从引入一段剪辑开始
I'll click here here on add clip and
我将点击此处添加剪辑和
we'll just bring in this clip of this
我们就把这段视频带进来
cyclist that we downloaded from pixabay
我们从Pixabay下载的自行车手
we can the clip appears over here in our
我们可以看到这段视频出现在我们的
project bin we can click play clip and
项目栏我们可以点击播放剪辑和
see what this looks like at normal speed
看看这在正常速度下是什么样子
let's go ahead and speed this up
让我们继续前进 加快速度
actually we'll speed up and slow down to
实际上 我们会加速和减速到
a couple things to it so I'm gonna pause
有几件事 所以我要暂停一下
it we can just drag right here on this
我们可以把它拖到这里
clip monitor if we click right here
如果我们点击这里 剪辑监视器
anywhere in the video we can drag it
我们可以将它拖到视频中的任何位置
down to our timeline
精确到我们的时间表
it didn't go quite go and then we can
不是很顺利 然后我们就可以
also we could have also click and drag
此外 我们还可以点击并拖动
it from here to what we can't do is drag
从这里到我们不能做的是拖拽
it from a file in our computer we can't
从我们电脑里的一个文件里我们不能
drag it there unless it's in our clip
将它拖到那里 除非它在我们的剪辑中
monitor already so we can drag into our
已经安装了监视器 这样我们就可以拖入我们的
clip our clip project bin but we can't
剪辑我们的剪辑项目垃圾箱 但我们不能
drag it into I don't we can drag it into
把它拖到我不知道我们可以拖到
the clip monitor or not now we can't
不管有没有剪辑监视器 现在我们都不能
drag it anywhere the only place we can
把它拖到我们唯一能找到的地方
drive from our computer is into the
驱动器从我们的计算机进入了
project bin and then from project bin we
BIN项目 然后从我们BIN项目
can drag into our timeline anyway so now
无论如何都可以拖到我们的时间线上 所以现在
we have it we have two copies of the
我们有 我们有两份
same video down here we only want one so
同样的视频在这里 我们只想要一个 所以
I'm gonna delete the second one by
我要删除第二个 通过
hitting the Delete key on my keyboard
按键盘上的Delete键
then I'll select this one we know what
那我就选这个吧 我们知道
selected cuz as the red box around it
选择CUZ作为其周围的红色框
and I'm going to come down here to the
我将来到这里 来到
bottom right and just make this a little
右下角 把这个弄得有点
bit larger alright I mean make my
好的 再大一点 我是说把我的
timeline view larger the video is
时间轴视图越大 视频越大
staying the same size we see it's still
保持同样的大小 我们看到它仍然是
the same speed that it's always been but
一如既往的速度 但
we are in our project monitor so we're
我们在我们的项目监控中 所以我们
watching it down here we know that -
在这里看着它 我们知道-
because our playhead is moving along
因为我们的游戏头在向前移动
with the video
与视频一起
whereas if we're gonna clip monitor and
但如果我们要剪掉监视器
we hit play it'll play this clip and our
我们点击播放它将播放这个剪辑和我们的
playhead down here staying still even
这里的花花公子保持不动 甚至
though our video is playing up here
虽然我们的视频在这里播放
that's the way you can tell which
这就是你能分辨出
monitor you're on and yeah so now we're
监视器 你打开了 是的 所以现在我们
going to take and apply the effect to
要将该效果应用于
this clip to do that we go to motion
这个片段要做的是 我们开始运动
left click on the speed effect and drag
在速度效果上单击鼠标左键并拖动
it over top of the clip now it says
它现在超过了剪辑的顶部 它说
speed in the top left corner of the clip
剪辑左上角的速度
and also we have some new properties
此外 我们还有一些新的特性
that weren't here before there's just
以前不在这里的只有
one control for speed and that is it's
一种速度控制 那就是它
in percentage so the percentage right
以百分比表示 因此百分比正确
now is 100% that means it's just playing
现在是100% 这意味着它只是在玩
normal speed if we want to go twice as
正常速度如果我们想要两倍的速度
fast we can change this we can click and
我们可以快速更改这一点 我们可以点击并
change it to 200% and hit enter and that
将其更改为200% 然后按Enter键即可
automatically shortens down the length
自动缩短长度
of our clip because now it's playing
因为现在它正在播放
twice as fast so it's going to take half
两倍的速度 所以要花一半的时间
the time to play does that make sense so
玩耍的时间有意义吗？
we can come back and play this and see
我们可以回来玩这个 看看
what it looks like fast pretty cool
它看起来很快 很酷
maybe we want it to be slow so we can
也许我们希望它慢一点 这样我们就可以
change it we can also just click and
更改它 我们也可以只需点击和
drag up in here but it's little bit
拖到这里来 但它有一点
sensitive on my computer I think it
我的电脑上很敏感 我想
depends on what operating system you're
取决于您使用的操作系统
using we can change it we can see it
使用我们可以改变它 我们可以看到它
just changes the size dynamically down
只是动态地向下改变大小
there let's change it down to about 58%
我们把它调低到58%左右吧
so this will be almost half speed so now
所以这几乎是一半的速度 所以现在
if we play everything should be really
如果我们打球 一切都应该是真的
slow so that's about half the normal
速度很慢 所以这大约是正常的一半
speed it would it would normally be
它的速度是正常的
maybe what I want to have happen to get
也许我想要的恰好得到了
rid of all the effects out of this we
抛开所有的影响 我们
just delete it or we can click on these
只需删除它 或者我们可以点击这些
three lines and go reset effect and that
三行和GO重置效果和那个
resets it back to what everything what
将其重置为什么一切什么
normally was which is 100% so we're back
通常是100% 所以我们回来了
to normal speed let's do this let's I'm
回到正常的速度 让我们开始吧 让我
just left clicking on the playhead right
只需左键点击播放头 右键点击
now and I'm kind of scrubbing along to
现在 我正在努力地去做
us find a certain point how about as
我们找到了某个点 怎么样？
soon as he touches the bike let's have
他一碰自行车 我们就开始
it go into slow motion right here so to
它在这里变成了慢动作 所以
do that if I want to have different
如果我想要不一样的话就这么做吧
portions of this video will be different
此视频的部分内容将有所不同
speeds I need to cut the clip otherwise
我需要的速度来削减剪辑 否则
it applies the effect to the entire clip
它将效果应用于整个剪辑
and in fact before I do this I'm just
事实上 在我这么做之前 我只是
going to delete the effect so now
现在要删除该效果
there's no effect at all applied to this
对此没有任何影响
clip and I'll go to my razor tool which
夹子 我去拿我的剃须刀
is this good as this little scissor
这个和这把小剪刀一样好吗？
cursor and I'll click right here and now
光标 我现在就在这里点击
I've cut this clip so we'll go back to
我把这段剪辑剪了下来 让我们回到
my selection tool now I have this clip
我的选择工具现在我有了这个剪辑
here and then this clip here so I will
这里 然后是这个片段 所以我会
apply a speed to this first clip
将速度应用于此第一个剪辑
and the speed we want is gonna be 200%
我们想要的速度是200%
so I'll change this to 200 hit enter it
因此 我将其更改为200次点击Enter It
shrinks that clip down by half because
将剪裁幅度缩小一半 因为
it's taking up less space now it's
它现在占用的空间更少了
playing twice as fast so I want to
打得快一倍 所以我想
left-click and drag this over so they
左键单击并将其拖到其上 以便他们
play seamlessly so now it's gonna play
玩得天衣无缝 所以现在它要播放了
really fast and then it's going to
非常快 然后它就会
slowly go back to normal speed so here
慢慢地回到正常速度 所以在这里
it's like running to his bike and then
就像跑到他的自行车前 然后
it slows down then maybe right here
它会放慢速度 然后可能就在这里
where he jumps on the bike I mean go
他跳上自行车的地方 我是说去
back a little bit there by left clicking
通过左键单击向后退回一点
and holding to about here I'm gonna go
坚持到这里 我要走了
back to my razor tool and I'm gonna cut
回到我的剃须刀工具前 我要切开
the video here because I want this last
这个视频是因为我想要这最后一个
part of the video to be another speed so
视频的一部分是另一种速度 所以
this one I want to be has come forward a
这位我想成为的人已经站出来了
little bit till it gets on the bike and
有一点 直到它上了自行车
then we'll clip it right here I'm gonna
然后我们就把它夹在这里 我要
go back to my selection tool so now I
返回到我的选择工具 现在我
have my ending part of the video which I
有我视频的结尾部分 我
can just drag it over here and watch and
可以把它拖到这里来看
see what it's playing like this is just
看看它在播放什么 就像这只是
him riding off at normal speed that's
他以正常的速度骑走了
how I want the ending to be but this
我想要怎样的结局 但这是
middle part I want to be slower so when
中间部分 我想慢一点 所以当
I slow it down it's gonna push out the
我让它慢下来 它会把
video make it longer so just so I don't
视频让它变得更长 所以我不会
get into any trouble with it like over
陷入任何麻烦 就像结束了一样
trying to push into this existing video
正在努力推进这段现有的视频
I'm gonna move this one up to the video
我要把这个移到录像带上
layer to our video track 2 and now I
层到我们的视频轨道2 现在我
should be able to take this clip and I
应该可以把这段视频和我
want this to be slow so it's a hundred
我想让它慢一点 所以是100
percent now and I want it to be OH so
现在的百分比 我想要它是哦 所以
since there was actually an effect
因为实际上有一种效果
applied to this it keeps them on all of
应用到这一点 它使它们保持在所有
these we noticed our first one is two
我们注意到我们的第一个是两个
hundred percent and then when we split
百分之百 然后当我们分手的时候
we just have a bunch of effects at one
我们只有一堆特效
hundred percent so I have to reapply it
百分之百 所以我必须重新涂抹
but if I did if there was no effect on
但如果我这样做了 如果不影响
it I have to read drag it down so let's
如果我不得不读 把它拖下来 所以让我们
do that so I'll make sure the effect is
这样我就能确保效果是
on and I'll change this down to 50
开着 我会把这个改成50
percent on this clip so sure enough it
在这个剪辑上的百分比是如此确定
pushed it out there it wasn't so far
把它推出去了 不是很远
that it ran into this so I'll drag this
它撞上了这个 所以我会拖着这个
back down and I use these tracks a lot
退后 我经常使用这些曲目
of time you can even like temporarily
你甚至可以暂时喜欢的时间
just drag it down to the audio track if
如果出现以下情况 只需将其拖到音频轨道上
ever you want to just get something out
你有没有想过只想说点什么
of the way or you're not sure where
或者你不确定在哪里
you're gonna add it in it's fine just to
你要把它加进去就行了
have just different parts of Clips
只是剪辑的不同部分
hanging out as long as you remember what
只要你记得什么 就一起出去玩
they are that's not a problem I actually
他们是 那不是问题 我实际上
use the timeline when I'm
使用时间线 当我
editing to just kind of store stuff and
编辑只是一种存储的东西
if I don't end up using it I'll just
如果我最后不用它 我就会
delete it sometimes or I'll drag it into
有时删除它 否则我会把它拖到
place right last minute but that's a
就在最后一分钟 但那是一个
good way to use the timeline these other
利用这些时间线的好方法
tracks even if you're not gonna render
轨迹 即使您不打算渲染
on those tracks it's a good place to
在那些轨道上 这是一个很好的地方
just kind of set stuff while you're
只是一些固定的东西 而你
waiting anyway so now everything's here
不管怎样都在等 所以现在一切都在这里
in the same one track so I'm gonna go
在同一条轨道上 所以我要走了
back to the beginning and we'll play
回到起点 我们来玩
this and we'll see what it looks like so
这样我们就会看到它是什么样子的
he ran quickly to get it he slowly gets
他跑得很快 他慢慢地拿到了
on then it goes back to normal speed and
然后它就会回到正常速度
rides off very cool so to accomplish
骑行很酷 所以要完成
this multiple speed we have this one at
这个倍速我们有这个速度
double speed 200% this one's at 100% the
双速200%这个速度是100%
next one's at 50% so half speed and the
下一个速度是50% 所以速度减半
last ones 100% again I'm gonna change
最后一次100%再一次 我要改变
this into 200% so he rides off quickly
这变成了200% 所以他很快就离开了
and there we have it and then to render
在那里 我们有它 然后呈现
this out this is the only effect we're
这是我们唯一的影响
gonna we're gonna keep on this whole
我们将继续保持这一切
thing to render it out I'll just click
要渲染它 我只需点击
render I'll click select mp4 I'll click
渲染我会点击选择MP4我会点击
this button here to choose a place to
点击这里的按钮 选择一个地方
render it to so it'll be desktop and
将其渲染到 使其成为桌面和
we'll call it speed bike so what I'm
我们会叫它速度自行车 所以我是
gonna call mine hit save and then I'll
我会叫我的命中扑救然后我会
hit this render to file so it'll render
点击这个渲染到文件 这样它就会渲染
it was it'll create this video and save
它将创建这段视频并保存
it on my desktop now and it takes a
它现在在我的桌面上 它需要一个
little bit of time has to go through and
只需要一点时间
process and it's like okay what are we
过程 就像是好的 我们是什么
doing we're slowing down this part of
我们正在放慢这一部分的速度
the video we're speeding up this part of
我们在这部分加速播放的视频
the video but it'll apply all those
视频 但它将应用所有这些
effects so just remember sometimes it
所以要记住 有时候
might be really laggy up here when
在这里可能真的很落后 当
you're watching in your project monitor
你在你的项目监视器里看着
but when you render it out it gets rid
但当你把它渲染出来时 它就会被去掉
of all that wagging as' and smoothness
在所有的摇摆和顺滑中
and makes it a nice crispy video so
并使其成为一个不错的易碎视频
we'll play this video here and this is
我们在这里播放这段视频 这是
what it looks like so we've kind of got
它看起来是什么样子 所以我们有一些
this slow and you've quickly rides off
这么慢 你很快就骑走了
so that is using the speed tool the
所以这就是使用速度工具
speed effect in kdenlive to either speed
Kdenlive中的速度效果为任一速度
up or slow down a video there was one
把视频调快或放慢有一段
more thing I was gonna say about this oh
关于这件事我还有更多要说的哦
yes so this video it happened to not
是的 所以这段视频恰好不是
have any audio associated with it but if
是否有任何与其关联的音频 但如果
it did have audio it would have also
它确实有音频 它本来也有
sped up and slowed down at the audio so
一听到音频就加速和放慢速度
the audio would be like slower and lower
音频就会变得越来越慢
or be super fast and high-pitched like
或者是像这样超快和高音
the chipmunks so just keep that in mind
花栗鼠 所以请记住这一点
if you are doing with audio this speed
如果你用这个速度来处理音频
effect will also apply
效力亦将适用
change the speed of that audio as well
同时更改该音频的速度
and check out a couple tutorials ago I
并在我之前查看几个教程
showed you how to actually even
向你展示了如何实际平衡
right-click and go to split audio and
右键单击并转到拆分音频和
that'll actually split the audio out of
这实际上会将音频从
your video clip if you want us to leave
你的视频剪辑 如果你想让我们离开
the audio or you can click over here and
音频或您可以点击此处并
mute the audio as well well I hope
我希望把音频也调成静音
you've enjoyed watching this video go
你很喜欢看这段视频
ahead and catch I'll catch you on the
在前面接住我会在
next one in the next tutorial we're
在下一个教程中
going to be changing we're going to be
我们将会改变
applying a crop to the video so we'll
在视频上加上一个裁剪
change we can zoom in and look at just
我们可以放大观察
one portion of the video and we'll also
视频的一部分 我们还将
learn how to how to move around the
学习如何移动周围的
video and transform it so catch on that
视频和转换它 所以赶上
video if you're interested go ahead and
视频 如果你有兴趣 继续
like comment subscribe and we'll see you
喜欢评论订阅 我们会看到你的
next video
下一个视频